lvan Frantar

Product Design

Work experience

Head of Design @ Aerlytix (formerly part of Stellwagen) | 01.2020 - Present

- Hands-on designing the product, investigating and solving business problems in a complex domain driven environment.
- Collaborating closely with project managers & executive stakeholders to navigate requirements while providing iterative, thoughtful solutions.
- Defining design principles that transmit to every aspect design is involved in the company and the business.
- Creating operational processes and practices for the creative vision and branding of Aerlytix.
- Leading and coordinating and leading marketing and communication initiatives.

Senior Product Designer @ Stellwagen Group | 01.2017 - 2020

- Bridging design with C-level and members of the Group for the strategic direction of the tools and products built.
- Shaping up a culture of design within the company amongst a team of technologists, engineers and quantitative modellers running design reviews, sprints and critiques.
- Implemented Product Market Fit research template viability of projects proposals.
- Built and coded a Design System library.

Senior Product Designer @ CurrencyFair | 07.2013 - 12.2016

- UI/UX design & frontend development (JavaScript, SASS, CSS3, HTML5).
- Responsive design implementation.
- Prototyping & wireframing for mobile apps & web.
- Established style with Twitter Bootstrap & Brand guidelines for Marketing
- Optimization for user behaviors using tools like Visual Web Optimizer, Google Analytics, Mixpanel.
- Conducted usability workshops with lead devs & project managers for flow & engagement enhancements.
- Mentored designers in system settings, Git usage, debugging, crossplatform compatibility.
- Organized design critiques & sprints for idea validation & improvement.

Lead Mobile UX Designer @ Hostelworld | 07.2010 - 12.2013

• I led UI/UX design for Mobile Sites and Apps (Android & iPhone) at Hostelworld and Hostels.com, collaborating closely with Product Head, PMs, and Developers.

Web Designer & Developer @ Hostelworld | 10.2007 - 07.2010

- I was hired to design and enhance the experience on a new product offering Hostelworld was creating: boo.com which won the 2008 Spider Award to best travel website.
- Worked in the other products and brands the company had such as hostels.com, trav.com, bedandbreakfastworld.com in a number of different initiatives in my capacity as a designer and developer.

Email: ivan@ivanfrantar.comPhone: +353 85 160 4834Web: ivanfrantar.com

Linkedin:linkedin.com/in/ivanfrantarDribbble:dribbble.com/ifrantarGithub:github.com/ifrantar

Profile

Passionate Product Designer crafting intuitive mobile/web experiences. Expert in crafting the end-to-end user flows, interaction design, and iterative improvement through user research, testing, and data analysis.

Skills

UI & Interaction Design
Design Systems
User Research
Design Thinking Methodologies
Workshops and Brainstorming sessions
Branding and Content Strategy
Wireframing
Prototyping
Mentoring

Design Software

Figma, Sketch, Miro
Adobe Creative Suite, Affinity
Principle for Mac
Google and Microsoft Office apps

Development tools

HTML, CSS & SASS, Javascript Visual Studio Code Github iTerm (Terminal & Vim)

Education

Bachelor (w/ Honors) in Software Systems

2006 - 2010 - National College of Ireland

Web Design and Electronic Publishing Diploma

2002-2005 - Minneapolis Community and Technical College

Journalism Degree

1996-2000 - Universidad Nacional de Cuyo